<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"> <channel><title>AsBuiltReport</title><description>Document Your Datacenter With PowerShell</description><link>https://www.asbuiltreport.com/</link><atom:link href="https://www.asbuiltreport.com/feed_rss_updated.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><managingEditor>Tim Carman</managingEditor><language>en</language> <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 23:21:19 -0000</pubDate> <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 23:21:19 -0000</lastBuildDate> <ttl>1440</ttl> <generator>MkDocs RSS plugin - v1.17.3</generator> <image> <url>None</url> <title>AsBuiltReport</title><link>https://www.asbuiltreport.com/</link> </image> <item> <title>The history of AsBuiltReport</title> <author>Tim Carman</author> <category>General</category> <description>&lt;h1&gt;The history of AsBuiltReport&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Beginning&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back in 2017, having worked on designing and implementing VMware solutions for almost a decade, I became frustrated with having to repeatedly produce as-built documentation for my virtualisation projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the time, I was designing and implementing 2-3 VMware solutions per month. Each solution would be designed using numerous technology partners, each with their own range of compute, storage, networking and backup technologies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My methods to create as-built documentation was arduous, time consuming and error prone. It often involved extracting information using a combination of vendor supplied tools and community developed scripts, and manually transposing information from the vCenter console into a Word document. It was tedious and often resulted in a poorly constructed and formatted document.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was also around this time that I realised I had a strong desire to learn PowerShell after seeing many of my co-workers starting to write scripts to automate simple, repeatable tasks. Until this moment, I had never taken the time to completely understand the fundamentals of PowerShell, nor had I worked to develop and expand my knowledge in any form of scripting or automation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a result, I saw this as an opportunity to learn and employ PowerShell automation to ease my pain and frustrations with producing as-built documentation. And so began my mission to create AsBuiltReport!&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.asbuiltreport.com/blog/2023/08/25/the-history-of-asbuiltreport/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 23:21:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.asbuiltreport.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">AsBuiltReport</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.asbuiltreport.com/blog/2023/08/25/the-history-of-asbuiltreport/</guid> <enclosure url="https://www.asbuiltreport.com/assets/images/social/blog\posts\The-history-of-As-Built-Report.png" type="image/png" length="46302" /> </item> <item> <title>The future of AsBuiltReport</title> <author>Tim Carman</author> <category>General</category> <description>&lt;h1&gt;The future of AsBuiltReport&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&#34;../posts/The-history-of-As-Built-Report.md&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; I shared how I came to start AsBuiltReport and my reasons for doing so. It&#39;s been a few years since its inception and some of you may be asking what does the future hold for the project?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before I delve into what may lie ahead, let me take a moment to reflect on the project&#39;s progression so far, by extending a sincere thank you to all the &lt;a href=&#34;../../about/contributors.md&#34;&gt;contributors&lt;/a&gt; who have given their time and effort to this project. Whether you have contributed code, reported bugs, provided feedback, written a blog post, or simply participated in discussions, your efforts have not gone unnoticed.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://www.asbuiltreport.com/blog/2023/12/05/The-future-of-As-Built-Report/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 23:21:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.asbuiltreport.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">AsBuiltReport</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.asbuiltreport.com/blog/2023/12/05/The-future-of-As-Built-Report/</guid> <enclosure url="https://www.asbuiltreport.com/assets/images/social/blog\posts\The-future-of-As-Built-Report.png" type="image/png" length="49889" /> </item> <item> <title>Multilingual support is coming soon to AsBuiltReport</title> <author>Tim Carman</author> <category>Announcements</category> <category>Features</category> <description>&lt;h1&gt;Multilingual support is coming soon to AsBuiltReport&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today I can announce that one of the most requested features for AsBuiltReport is currently in development, with work underway to bring &lt;strong&gt;multilingual support&lt;/strong&gt; to the AsBuiltReport framework.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;multilingual&#34; src=&#34;../../assets/images/blog/multilingual.jpg&#34;&gt;{ loading=lazy }&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Key Features in Development&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🌐 Comprehensive Localization Framework&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Implementation of PowerShell&#39;s built-in localization capabilities&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Option for differing UI localization and report localization&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;📝 Standardised Translation Structure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Standardised folder structures for simple multilingual support adoption&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Support for resource files containing translated strings for AsBuiltReport core and report modules&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Automated string extraction and translation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔧 New Commandline Parameters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dynamic language selection - language selection is determined by what each AsBuiltReport module supports&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Support for standard locale codes (en-US, es-ES, fr-FR, de-DE, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fallback mechanism to ensure reports generate even with incomplete translations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;📊 Report Module Integration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Documentation and templates for new and existing report modules to add multilingual support&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Backward compatibility ensuring existing English-only workflows continue to work&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Progressive enhancement allowing modules to adopt localization incrementally&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>https://www.asbuiltreport.com/blog/2025/09/05/Multilingual-support/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 23:21:41 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.asbuiltreport.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">AsBuiltReport</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.asbuiltreport.com/blog/2025/09/05/Multilingual-support/</guid> <enclosure url="https://www.asbuiltreport.com/assets/images/social/blog\posts\Multilingual-support-coming-soon.png" type="image/png" length="55701" /> </item> </channel></rss>